Jakub Lizak

j.lizak@yahoo.com

+48 509 185 882

Whatsapp: +48 509 185 882

Krakow, Poland

Software development manager

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Team leader and manager with software development processes expertise. Servant, versatile and flexible leader with agile mindset and quality awareness, working with teams and highly skilled engineers helping them to achieve goals, improve productivity, collaboration, communication

team integrity and job satisfaction.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Leading teams, coaching and mentoring, continuous improvement, communication: written and spoken, team and cross team collaboration, software development processes: both waterfall and

agile, testing and software development process improvements.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2019.01 - now

Company: Sabre Corporation, Krakow, Poland

Product: Sabre reservation systems (Trip Data Service) - team is focused on designing,

developing and maintaining variety of Order (aka travel record according to NDC - New

Distribution Capability, IATA) services running on open systems. We are responsible for Order

data distribution to internal and external customers, hosting multiple Order management

services and building Order data store in modern, scalable, microservice based and Cloud

oriented architecture. We employ latest technologies and practices to handle high volume of

transactions supporting millions of traveling passengers daily.

Role: <u>Software development manager</u>, duties:

- managing and leading work of 3 scrum teams (1 offshore team in India)

- removing obstacles for successful project delivery

- improving Agile with Scrum processes

- projects coordination: scope, planning, development and test automation

1/4

- communicating blockers and obstacles regarding project deliverables to all of the stakeholders
- defects management: coordination of 6 BA/TPMs effort of defects analysis
- maintaining communication with Product Owners/Account managers of different BUs regarding projects deliverables and defect fixes
- hiring new team members
- coaching and mentoring team members in their professional development
- motivating and support for team members, peers and colleagues

2017.09 - 2018.12

Company: Sabre Corporation, Krakow, Poland

Product: Sabre reservation systems (**Trip Data Service**)

Role: Software development in test manager/QA manager, duties:

- managing software development in test teams to achieve project goals
- improving software development process towards CI/CD software development approach
- hiring new team members
- setting career plans and goals for employees, supporting personal and professional development
- communicating blockers and obstacles regarding project deliverables to all of the stakeholders
- removing obstacles for successful project delivery
- coordinating releases testing and and improving testing approach

2015.12 - 2017.9

Company: Sabre Corporation, Krakow, Poland

Sabre Dynamic Retailer promotes ancillary growth by dynamically creating flight and ancillary offers using personalized customer insights to generate incremental revenue. It also enables an airline to identify and offer the most relevant services and product bundles to travellers.

Role: Software development in test supervisor/QA supervisor

- working in Agile with SCRUM methodology
- managing team of software development in test engineers
- leading software development in tests teams in achieving project goals
- improving process towards CI/CD software development approach
- hiring new team members

- setting career plans and goals for employees, supporting personal and professional development
- communicating blockers and obstacles regarding project deliverables to project's stakeholders
- removing obstacles for successful project delivery
- coordinating releases testing and improving testing approach

2014.11 - 2015.12

Company: Sabre Corporation, Krakow, Poland

Product: Sabre Dynamic Retailer

Role: acting Software development in test lead/QA lead, duties:

- leading test automation towards CI/CD approach
- optimizing test coverage based on business use cases for the product
- validating and testing releases for production
- mentoring new team members

5.2014 - 10.2014

Company: John Lewis UK/EPAM, Krakow, Poland / London, UK

role: Test Team Leader, duties:

- Leading testing team
- Defining testing standards: process, test strategies, tools selection
- Mentoring new team members

9.2004 -11.2012

Company: Motorola/Nokia Siemens Networks, Krakow, Poland

role: Software Engineer/Automation and testing expert, Scrum master, duties:

- test automation: developing testing framework and automating test scenarios, test case creation and execution
- software engineering: testing CDMA/WCDMA/LTE infrastructure elements
- leading new feature test automation
- mentoring and teaching new team members
- process improvements

LANGUAGES:

English – good, written and spoken Polish – native

EDUCATION:

AGH University of Science and Technology: Electronics and Telecommunications – MSc (4.5) SWPS University of Social Science and Humanities: Psychology – MA (5.0)

INTERESTS: indie movies, contemporary and classical music, cooking